Last video we had a look at the dlmalloc implementation of free().
我们发现了unlink（）宏，它可以用来将几乎任意的数据写入
another address.
我们用gdb构造了一个概念证明堆，并观察到对
global offset table.
但最终我们意识到，我们的计划行不通，因为它包含了太多
null-bytes and we can’t write those with strcpy.
让我们快速回顾和总结一下我们对堆和自由算法的了解
to refine our exploitation plan.
最后一段视频更具探索性，带您了解如何发现漏洞
yourself, but this video will be more of a presentation.
这样我们就有了不同风格的关于同一主题的视频，我希望增加
the amount of people who understand how it works.
So let’s look again at how a heap chunk looks like.
当您分配某个大小的块时，该块的大小将写入
2nd word and malloc will return the address here.
This means you have this area for user data.
The last bits of the chunk size have special meaning.
Most importantly the last bit is the previous in use bit.
So that is information about the chunk BEFORE the current chunk.
So that’s a little bit weird to wrap your head around at the beginning.
这意味着如果在这里分配了这个块，那么后面的块将具有最后一个
bit set.
Because the chunk in front of it is in use.
Now a free chunk could contain more information.
所以一旦我们释放了这个块，很明显我们可以将块的最后一位设置为
0.
To indicate that the previous chunk is not in use anymore.
Now imagine there is a third chunk.
A chunk after the 2nd one, which has it’s previous in use bit NOT set.
This means the 2nd chunk is free.
Now the algorithm would like to merge, consolidate those two blocks.
This is where the two words after the size start being important.
They are the forward and backward pointer.
Just as a sidenote, this only applies to chunks that are bigger than the fastbin size.
Because fastbins are very small chunks and they don’t use a double linked list.
So our chunks are bigger.
Let’s consider this heap setup.
We have a chunk we want to free, which is followed by an already free chunk.
这个自由块有两个指针，向前和向后指向另一个自由块
chunks.
So they are in this double linked list.
Now what will happen is, the free algorithm will merge these two blocks together.
它将首先通过使用“取消链接”从链接列表中取消自由块的链接来实现这一点。
macro.
我们知道了它的作用，它把前向地址写在
the forward pointer of the previous chunk.
它将获取反向地址并将其写入
next chunk.
当我们明显地控制了一个自由块的指针，它将被取消链接，我们
can point into the global offset table and write there the forward address.
In the last video we stopped here and didn’t check out what happens next.
But let me tell you now.
接下来，我们将增加释放的块的大小
free block.
And then we will insert this block into the double linked list.
Which means we take one chunk, and look up it’s forward chunk.
And then we update the pointers accordingly to now include our chunk.
This is the whole magic of the heap.
现在让我们回到著名的短语文章“Once on a free”和“Vudo malloc”
tricks” to see what they tell us about the unlink exploit.
Both articles contain a cool little trick to overcome the limitations of the null-byte.
因此，当我们想要构造一个可以取消链接的假块时，我们要确保
no field has to contain a null-byte.
This means we have to use very very large values for the size.
But that doesn’t seem useful, because the heap is not that big.
Mh.
但是在文章中展示的聪明的想法是利用计算机处理负面信息的方式。
values.
因此，让我们快速探索32位整数值会发生什么，当我们添加一个
very large number.
For example fffffffC.
That would be over 4 billion.
现在，当你加上0x64时会发生什么，它是十进制100到40亿？
That doesn’t fit in 32bit.
And the carry of the addition will be lost.
And now you have a very small value again.
In fact it’s 0x60.
Which is 4 less than 0x64.
This means by adding 4 billion, the ffffffc to 100, we actually subtracted 4.
And that’s a really useful behaviour for our case.
Because this value that doesn’t contain any null-bytes behaves like a very small subtraction.
So when we skim over the sourcecode again, we can now make a plan.
首先，我们必须用一个大于
80.
So let’s do the 100 like last video.
但是我们也不关心前一次的合并尝试
block.
This ways we don’t have to setup another fake chunk.
So we make sure that the last bit of the block we are going to free is set to 1.
So it’s still in use.
But we could do the consolidate forward part.
在这里，我们取下一个块，从它的下一个块中检查上一个正在使用的块，以及
if that is not set, we attempt to unlink, consolidate that block.
这意味着我们需要两个假块，一个包含向前和向后指针
we want to use to overwrite the GoT with an address from the heap.
And the second chunk has to have a size with the lowest bit set to 0.
BUT we can’t use small size values.
但是，如果您在代码中查看大小是如何使用的，它只是用作一个添加的偏移量。
to an address.
The code doesn’t check that it’s a ridiculous huge chunk.
It just adds that value.
And here is where the trick comes into play.
We could use fffffffc as the size of the chunk, which results in a -4.
Now think what will happen.
它将占用该块的大小，并将其添加到当前地址以查找下一个
chunk, which fools free into thinking the next chunk is at -4 from here.
现在它将读取该块的大小，我们也可以将其设置为fffffff c，而不是
设置最后一个位并结束，是的，之前的块没有使用，让我们取消链接。
it.
嘘声！
It’s very beautiful and clever.
And doesn’t contain any null bytes.
So let’s see if we can fill that heap in a way that we can do that with strcpys.
So strcpy stops at a null-byte.
这意味着我们必须使用其中一个来溢出我们想要释放的块的大小。
100, 0x64.
Ehh.. obviously we want to prev in use bit set, so we need to overflow it with 0x65.
这是因为我们不想写更多，它以一个空字节结束，并且
keeps the size clean.
另一个strcpy可以用来填充100字节，直到奇怪的连体假的
chunks with ffffc, and afterwards the two addresses we want to write.
现在，就像前面的视频一样，我们将把一个地址设置为全局偏移表，
so that we overwrite puts, and the other one will be pointing into the first heap.
这意味着我们将把代码执行重定向到这个堆地址，并且可以使用第一个
strcpy to place some shellcode here.
请记住，取消链接也会将一些数据从全局偏移表写入
这堆区域，所以我们要么保持代码简短，要么跳过粉碎的
data and continue shellcode afterwards.
But we just want to call winner.
So let’s construct the exploit.
You could do it in one line, but let me break it up to makeit easier to follow.
In each of these windows we will construct one parameter, one string for each strcpy.
所以也许我们先来处理中间块的strcpy，因为它应该是
the one to overwrite the chunk size with 101 of the 3rd chunk.
我用echo来表示，我计算了达到
the chunk, where we then write 101, 0x65.
我将输出重定向到一个文件B中，然后我们可以将它与backticks和cat一起用作
parameter in gdb.
We can then run it and investigate the heap.
Looks perfect, the size of the third chunk is now 0x65.
接下来我们来处理第三个块，它在溢出之后，所以是100
byte big.
所以我们想写100个字符来填充数据块，然后最终到达
在下一块，我们要为前面的技巧编写fffff c，
followed by the global offset table address and the heap address.
Here I get the table address for puts and subtract -12 from it.
因为堆地址将写入
+12.
然后是最后一个strcpy，第一个块，我们想在其中包含shellcode
to call winner.
I quickly googled for an online assembler to create the shellcode.
We want to call an absolute address, to do this we have to go via a register.
So we could move the address of winner into eax and then call eax.
我们可以简单地复制这个shell代码的字符串表示形式并将其写入
file.
Cool.
Now that we have all thre parameters we can rerun the program.
So Let’s have a look at the heap.
It looks nice.
Let’s execute the free and single step into the puts call.
Oh.
great we follow into the heap, but somehow our shellcode is wrong.
You can see that it’s complete garbage.
Instead of our shellcode we have some addresses here.
哎哟！
Of course, we perform multiple frees, not just the one.
So we obviously write metadata over these values.
But we can simply fix that by pointing to a different area of the heap.
How about here at 14.
Now we change the address and prepend some characters to our shellcode. and try it again.
We run it, single step into puts and arrive at winner.
hehe.
让我们在没有gdb的情况下试试吧！
It worked.
天哪，我喜欢这个！